## **SAVAN PATEL**

Fremont, California 94555 | (510)-458 1828 | savanpatel750@gmail.com | Github | LinkedIn

### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Computer Science graduate student with 2.5+ years of experience as a Software Engineer, seeking internship opportunities or full-time opportunities for 2021. Extensive experience in Software and Web application development and also an Open Source Contributor.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Master of Science: Computer Science** 

Aug 2019 - May 2021

California State University East Bay, Hayward, CA, USA

Master of Science: Information Technology (GPA: 3.3)

Aug 2015 - Jun 2017

Dhirubhai Ambani Institute of Information and Communication Technology, Gandhinagar, India

**Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Engineering (GPA: 3.3)** 

Aug 2011 - Jun 2015

Gujarat Technological University, Ahmedabad, India

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Jun 2020 (Present)

SPILLBOX, San Jose, CA

- Working in Infrastructure as a Code using Azure and most of AWS services like EC2, S3, IAM, EFS.
- Using cloud provisioning tools such as Terraform to automate system operations.
- Working on Cloud Migrations to IAAS Platforms like AWS, Azure.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jul 2017 – Jul 2019

ZEUS LEARNING, Mumbai, India

- Worked on the features of eLearning Web App like Interactive whiteboard, Student collaboration, Formative assessments, Annotation clips, Whiteboard animation recorder, and Screen recorder. Used technologies like C#, JavaScript, Node Js, MySQL.
- Design and implemented the modules of Desktop Application like Remote desktop, Screen mirroring, Desktop screenshot capturer, Video streaming of desktop using WebRTC, Graphics programming using QT(C++) QPainter API for 2D Graphics, and Recording desktop screen. Real time communication is achieved with Packet programming. Used technologies like QT, C++, WebRTC, Web Sockets, JavaScript.

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN**

Jan 2017 - Apr 2017

ZEUS LEARNING, Mumbai, India

- Designed and implemented the module that converts the PDF files to the SVG files. Used Java library named PDFBox for parsing the PDF files and created the font files from PDF's embedded fonts.
- I further used CANVG to render the SVG files on the screen. Technologies used like Java, Maven, Eclipse.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Coding:** Java, C/C++, JavaScript, Python, Object oriented programming, Event driven architecture **Web Technologies:** Node Js, React Js, HTML/CSS, JSP, Servlets, C#, XML, JSON, AJAX, jQuery, Rest API

Database System: MySQL, MongoDB, NeDB

Frameworks: Express, QT Creator, Testing frameworks (Mocha and Chai), MVC

**Tools:** Eclipse, Android Studio, IntelliJ, QT, GIT, Jira, Redmine

#### **PROJECTS**

Pokedex Mobile App (https://github.com/antimaze/Pokedex)

2020

2020

Technologies: Java, Android Studio

 Created a Simple application in which it shows the list of Pokémon. Implemented features like Searching, Catching Pokémon with button, Saving the state of caught Pokémon, and loading the Pokémon data and its photo from API.

PhotoFilter Mobile App (https://github.com/antimaze/PhotoFilter)

Technologies: Java, Android Studio

• Designed and created application that can allow you to apply different types of filters like CropTransformation, BlurTransformation, SketchFilterTransformation etc. on Image. Also, user can save the filtered image on disk.

Notes (https://github.com/antimaze/Notes)

2020

Technologies: Java, Android Studio

• Created a note-taking application that can save data to the device. For saving the data to file, SQLite database is used which supports the SQL queries. It supports creating notes, editing notes and deleting the notes..

# Detect all faces in image (<a href="https://github.com/antimaze/Detect-all-faces-in-image">https://github.com/antimaze/Detect-all-faces-in-image</a>) Technologies: Python, pip

2020

• Created a simple face recognition program in python that detects all the faces of persons from the given image using "face\_recognition" library.

#### Message Parser Tool (https://github.com/antimaze/MessageParser)

2020

Technologies: Java, Maven, Eclipse

• Created a program that parse the messages contain in the text file and update the google sheet according to the parsed messages.

#### Tour Company (https://github.com/antimaze/TourCompany)

2019

Technologies: Node Js, React Js, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Git, NeDB database

Developed multi-user web application for a fictional tour company which manages its customers and tours.

#### XML Comparator (https://github.com/antimaze/XMLComparator)

2019

Technologies: Java, Maven, Design Patterns, Eclipse

• Created an XML Comparator which can parse two XML Files (Source and Target) and compare target file with source file and write XML differences in output file given in the input.

#### Albusbook (https://github.com/antimaze/albusbook)

2015

Technologies: Java, Servlet, JSP, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, AJAX, MVC Framework, Eclipse

• Developed the Social Networking Project like Twitter which supports the features like creating profile, search other peoples, follow/unfollow others, posting messages, Newsfeed, like others post, private messages, "People you may know" suggestion.